<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Lords-Justices and council. A proclamation. Charles Porter, Tho: Coningesby. Whereas their Majesties by their royal proclamation, dated at their camp by Dublin the tenth day of July, 1690. ...</title>
            <author>Ireland. Lords Justices and Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B24741</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886518</idno>
  <idno type="VID">186738</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248538635</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing I456</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide G. 5869[29]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R226122</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886518</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886518e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B24741)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 186738)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C5:3[29])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Lords-Justices and council. A proclamation. Charles Porter, Tho: Coningesby. Whereas their Majesties by their royal proclamation, dated at their camp by Dublin the tenth day of July, 1690. ...</title>
                  <author>Ireland. Lords Justices and Council.</author>
                  <author>Coningsby, Thomas Coningsby, Earl, 1656?-1729.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Andrew Crook assignee of Benjamin Took printer to the King and Queen at their Majesties printing-house on Ormonde-Key,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1691]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from caption and opening words of text.</note>
                  <note>"Given at the Council-Chamber in Dublin, the 23th day of February, 1690.".</note>
                  <note>The brass and copper coinage no longer current.--Steele.</note>
                  <note>Steele notation: Arms 201. Procla- said p.2) un- Mo-.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Money --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Coinage --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Ireland --  History --  War of 1689-1691 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:186738:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <head>
                     <figure>
                        <figDesc>monogram of 'W' (William) superimposed on 'M' (Mary)</figDesc>
                     </figure> RR</head>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon surmounted by a crown and flanked by the English lion and Tudor rose on one side and the Scottish unicorn and thistle on the other</figDesc>
                  <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <q xml:lang="frm">JE MEINTIENDRAY</q>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>BY THE Lords-Justices AND COUNCIL, A PROCLAMATION.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>CHARLES PORTER,</item>
                     <item>THO: CONINGESBY.</item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas Their Majesties by Their Royal Procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation, Dated at Their Camp by <hi>Dublin</hi> the Tenth day of <hi>July,</hi> 1690. In the Second Year of Their Majesties Reign, for the Reasons therein mentioned, did think fit to reduce certain Coins of Brass, Copper and mixt Mettal, which formerly were used in this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, and imposed upon the People at vast Rates, beyond and above the Intrinsick Value, to the several Rates in the said Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion mentioned, and did Ordain that the said Coins and Pieces should be deemed and ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken as Current Moneys in all payments at the several Rates therein con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained. Now forasmuch as it is found by Experience, that the <hi>Irish</hi> who are in Rebellion against Their Majesties, and have in their Possession the whole or the far greater part of the said Coin, do begin by secret and cun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning
<pb facs="tcp:186738:2"/> ways to bring in the said Coin into those Parts of this Kingdom un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der Their Majesties Obedience, wherewith they or their Agents not only fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nish Their Majesties Enemies with divers Goods, Provisions and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dities for supplying their Wants and Necessities; which they could not a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny other ways obtain but by this means, will bring such vast Quantities of the said Coin amongst Their Majesties good Subjects, as in the end will turn to Their Majesties great damage. We therefore taking the Premisses into Our Consideration, for providing a Remedy against this growing Evil, have thought fit hereby to Order, Publish and Declare, that from and after the Six and Twentieth day of this Instant <hi>February,</hi> none of the said Pie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces or Coyns in the said Proclamation mentioned, shall be Currant, or used in any Payments between any Persons whatsoever; Nor shall any of Their Majesties Loving Subjects be Compelled to take or Receive the same as Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney at any Rate or Price whatsoever.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given at the <hi>Council-Chamber</hi> in <hi>Dublin,</hi>
                  <date>the 23th Day of <hi>February,</hi> 1690. And in Third Year of their Majesties Reign.</date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>Fran Dublin,</item>
                     <item>Longford,</item>
                     <item>Anth. Midensis,</item>
                     <item>Rob. Fitz-Gerald,</item>
                     <item>Char. Meredith,</item>
                     <item>Ri. Reynell,</item>
                     <item>Ri. Pyne.</item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
               <lb/> God Save the KING and QUEEN.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Dublin,</hi> Printed by <hi>Andrew Crook</hi> Assignee of <hi>Benjamin Took</hi> Printer to the <hi>King</hi> and <hi>Queen</hi> at their <hi>Majesties</hi> printing-house on <hi>Ormonde-Key.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>